Emmet Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Nov 18, 1931 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Reunion in Vienna well received opening night; the Lunts; Mr. Moller, director of Strange Interlude; June Walker's baby boy; Bobby and Mary Sherwood dined with the A. A. Milnes
Nov 1931 - To: Jane - From: Posie (214 E 70th) - Subjects: first night of play--the Lunts and Cynthia; Connie's baby early in summer; Posie moves into apartment on Tuesday
Nov 24, 1931 - To: Lydia - From: Mrs. F. Wilder - Subjects: thanks for portraits of Bellamydaughter Mary Rutherford and Joan Bellamy
Nov 27, [1931] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: settled at 142 until new place ready; play sold out; Posie paints Pulitzer child; little Mary's friend is Kermit Roosevelt's daughter
Dec 3, [1931] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: all is not lost for Susie; Jane helped Lucien Monod; Lydia broke her arm 7 weeks ago; Lydia's portrait of Auerbach; Nora's baby; Art Workers' Fair; Bobby's premiere; Bobby fell at tennis; June and Geoffrey's baby boy
Dec 5, 1931 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Ginny Sherwood slipped through glass door
Dec 7, [1931] - To: ? - From: Lydia (fragment) - Subjects: the Lunts in Reunion in Vienna; Greta Kemble Cooper married Dr. Eskill; Edna Ferber; Marc Connelly; Anita Loos; John Emerson; Cornie and Bill; will finish Mr. Auerbach tomorrow; Mousie's baby boy; Dooly studies music at Julliard
Dec 25, [1931] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Christmas at Bobby's for the Lunts for Reunion in Vienna--miniatures by Posie; Norma Shearer wants the play; Kay Francis is from Pittsfield; Jane's charade party; Posie hopes to move to 216 E 70th by Feb 1; (drawing of miniature frames)
Dec 25, [1931] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (at Wheatley Hills) - Subjects: Lydia at Lybba's--Eddie Morgan neglects office now; Alty Morgan; Bessie White; Lizzie broke her leg 2 weeks ago; the Lunts; Lydia's protrait of "A"; Bay's portrait of Bob; Susie Ord spends Christmas with Bay
Dec 28, 1931 - To: Lydia - From: H.L.R. Emmet (works for G.E.) - Subject: picture of "The old Man" (Uncle Bill)
Dec 29, [1931] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: the Lunts; Reunion in Vienna; Florence and Langers; Elma Marsh saw Lybba after Zurich; Wilfrid's portraits of Booth Jones
Dec 31, 1931 - To: Lydia - From: H.L.R. Emmet - Subject: Uncle Bill's portrait
Jan 10, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Madie acting strangely; Lybba and Eddie; Lynn Fontanne has a cold
Jan 15, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lunts' movie The Guardsman; Reunion in Vienna booming; Lydia to live with Posie and rented her apartment to Tom LaFarge who is engaged to Marie Iselin; Ellen Biddle married Baron F___; Jane Lapsley's husband ok
Jan 23, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Madie had seizure; Lybba and Eddie troubles; Bobby's play sold to movie studio, another wanted it for Chevalier but Bobby didn't want it to be a musical; MGM wants Lunts
Feb 4, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Mabel Jenks and Bill James to tea; Bill is to paint a bishop; Tom LaFarge to paint in Lydia's studio; Ros in Baltimore; Lydia's party--the Lunts, Phil Merivale, the Eskills, Auerbach, the Masseys, June and Geoffrey, and "a young man doing Hamlet"
Feb 18, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Posie remembers seeing Nilsson watching Belle Helene 50 years ago; Posie on crutches--must give up Bermuda trip; won't move til autumn; Queen's Husband opened Monday; Bobby Sherwood wrote jokes for Doug's movie; Jim (Galloping Jim) Parker for tea
Feb 19, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia's portrait of Marga; Wilder Bellamy's father's portrait; Dorothy Peabody (Mrs. Trubee Davison); Mrs. Le Braz; Madie in sanitarium; Tom LaFarge's and Marie Iselin's wedding
Mar 4, 1932 - To: C. Temple Emmet - From: Mr. Lycett? - Subject: wants to sell portrait of Dr. Emmet and his wife
[1932] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Posie and Lydia bought portraits (Temple had first refusal); the Lunts; Reunion in Vienna; Coward wants the play for Gladys Cooper in London; the play Moon in the Yellow River; Elektra; Kilmainham Jail in Dublin for sale; Shaw's love letters to Mrs. Patrick Campbell and Ellen Terry; Bob and Mary have villa near St. Tropez; Lydia living with Posie
Mar 5, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Cartlidge next door; Lybba's last Sunday in Sycamore house; Eddie Morgan in sanitarium; Susie Ord; Eugene O'Neill married his third wife; Reunion in Vienna; LaFarge wedding; Susie (Metcalfe?) sails last of April; Nite's baby; Dennis Taylor's Peter Ibbetson; Lindbergh kidnapping; Leslie Chanler; Lydia finishing Marga's portrait; Wilfrid should take Mrs. [Davison's] offer; Wilfrid's Royal Academy
Mar 6, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Wilfrid and the Davison (Dorothy Peabody) order; Bobby gave profits from Queen's Husbandto disabled Canadian veterans; Maurice Colbourne; Bill and Mercury boiler article in paper; dined with Elizabeth Biddle, Bay, Leslie and Cornie
Mar 16, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Davison portraits; Ramsay portraits; Lydia and Susie
May visit Jane; Cecilia Beaux raved over the statue (bust); Flo and Langers; Joe Brisache; Bob and Mary; Susan Ord portrait; Herm and Helen's 20th anniversary in June
Mar 24, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: purchase of Emmet family portraits; little LaFarges; Lydia will do Susan Ord; Lydia to go to England in summer; the Jameses; Robert Emmet; Mary Sherwood too Yiddish; the Lunts; lunch at Mabel Jenks where Bill and Alice (James?) are staying; Bill James sent article by Tonks on modern art; Bill and Alice pleased about R. A.; Duveen's cable; Ned Carter suicide
Apr 2, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Forester Warner - Subject: information request re painting of Robert Temple
Apr 11, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Benjamin LaFarge born Apr 10 to Hetty and Bancel; Lydia paints Susan Ord; Bob and Mary birthday party parody on Reunion in Vienna--the Lunts, Phil Merivale, Marc Connelly and his wife and Geoff and June--Lybba brought Eddie who flirted with June; Gouve back from Orient
[Apr 1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: gossip about Mary--June Walker; Susie Ord; Lydia sails July 1; Bill's stocks dropped out; Lybba's x-ray treatments
Apr 4, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Forester Warner - Subject: wants to sell portrait of Robert Temple
Apr 13, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby and Mary's money habits; surprise party; Geoff and June's play closed after 2 weeks; Bobby and family to go to Paris and London
Apr 20, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Ros should play golf tournament in England; Elizabeth Biddle rented her apartment to Mrs. Marshall Field-Elizabeth to go to Germany until birth of Ellen's baby; Phil Merivale sent tickets for his play Cynara
Apr 27, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: ancestry; Frederika Auerbach's portrait; Lybba loves Susan Ord's portrait; Bill James;Lydia and Susie sail for Cannes June 24; Ros' sinus operation; Mabel Jenks; Toscanini at Mary Hayden's; Bob and Mary sail on Saturday
May 11, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Ros visits Jane; heard Noel Coward wants Reunion in Vienna for London; Coward wrote play for Lunts and himself too
May 11, [1932?] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: cover letter from Jane re Forester Warner's offer of Robert Temple portrait
May 15, 1932 - To: Lydia - From: Marcus T. Reynolds - Subject: Ord portrait
[May 1932] - To: [Jane] - From: Lydia - Subjects: the Cartlidges; Mr. Auerbach; Florence and Langers; Dolo's operation months ago--May be terminal; Lydia sails Jun 28 to reach Cannes
Jun 3, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Ros in England; a copy of Dorothy Parker poem; Ord portrait; Bill cheerful in spite of losses; Queen's Husband at Stockbridge Theater; Lunts to take Reunion in Vienna to London; Laura White's 8th child, Octavia, born--they live with Bessie White; Helen and Herman's 20th anniversary; Lydia plans trip abroad; Susie (Metcalfe); Bill invented new boiler; Mary Hayden and Mabel Choate; Grenville Hunter shot himself
Jun 6, 1932 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane just returned from Grantchester; Arthur Jr.'s temporary job; Ros now staying with Bobby Sherwood in Paris; Dolo's bad news
Jun 27, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (at Colony Club) - Subjects: Alty Morgan and Lizzie were horrid to Lybba; Gren Hunter shot himself; Lybba still sees Eddie; Susie's concert with Saslavsky
Jul 5, [1932] - To: Posie - From: Evelyn - Subjects: Betsy in Queen's Husband; Ros is good gambler
Jul 6, [1932] - To: Lydia - From: Betsy - Subject: Ros home tomorrow
Jul 6, 1932 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: meeting Ros; Claude Rains in The Queen's Husband
[Sep 1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Ros in Canada; Swan wedding; Lybba and Eddie at Chesapeake Bay house; the Lunts; Jeanne Millet
Oct 25, 1932 - To: Lydia - From: Kate Schley - Subject: thanks for portrait
Oct 30, [1932] - To: Jane (in Cannes) - From: Lydia (214 E 70th) - Subject: Lucy Bredin wants portrait of her and Anne; Lydia met Alice Fowler; Lybba and Eddie at Chesapeake Bay; Lydia prefers FDR to Hoover; Lydia mad at Mrs. Waring; Lydia to paint Clarisse; Guild turned down Bobby's play Acropolis; sell ancestoral portraits to Beulah
Nov 3, 1932 - To: Lydia - From: Lucien Monod(in French) - Subjects: Wilfrid and Jane--Lucien loves Lydia's portrait of Jane; Susie
Nov 19, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Posie (142 E 71st) - Subjects: Lydia to go to DC to paint Mrs. Hoover; Bobby making changes in Acropolis; Dooly is 18; Lunts rehearsing with Coward; Babs Gibson is now Mrs. Emery (her sister married Grandduke Dmitri--he loved Reunion in Vienna); Reunion in Vienna, Green Pastures, and The Barrets of Wimpole Street are the only profitable touring shows; Ros needs sinus operation
Nov 27, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia decided not to paint Lucy; finished blond child with black poodle; started on Rutherfords; Mrs. Hoover's portrait; Lybba;to Mary Hayden's for dinner; Lydia enjoyed summer at Wilton; Exhibition "Fifty Years of American Art"; Art Workers' Fair; Toscanini; Ros' operation; Dev's nervous breakdown
Dec 1932 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter(7 Montagu St.) - Subject: Christmas greetings
Dec 14, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia was happy with Jane this summer; world politics; Lydia will paint Mrs. Hoover; Roosevelt; Bobby's opinion of Congress; Dorothy Potter; Leslie; Geoffrey Kerr; sat between Susie Ord and Anne Choate at Maria's lunch; Susie heard via Clara Passigli that Pablo loves her; Art Workers' Fair
Dec 18, [1932] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Mrs. Hoover's appearance; Lydia to paint her in February; Bob and Mary go to Indianapolis; Betsy in play Girls in Uniform
Dec 30, 1932 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lydia had a bad spell; Christmas at Bobby's; Joe Alsop is Mrs. Douglas Robinson's grandson and is a Tribune reporter; the play Acropolis; Bobby is writing a screenplay about Malibu Beach; Lydia has watercolor by Lucien Monod
Jan 2, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia's teeth; Lydia paints little Sally; Wee wed soon to Henry Bartol; Posie did watercolor portrait of Henry for Gouve; Winty made A.D. Club; Lybba visited Madie; Roger and Dinah; Posie dined with the Menuhins; Mary Hayden; Lybba and Eddie; (drawing of sewing bag)
Jan 13, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia goes to Washington, DC on Monday; finished Clarisse's head; gratifying about Susie and Yehudi; copy of Susie's letter to Mox Kobbe about Pablo (?)
Jan 14, 1933] - To: Jane - From: Posie (142 E 71) - Subjects: re Grandpa's childhood; Ros' portrait of Mrs. Russell of 2 years ago; Jane to see George Greene; Bobby's play; Miss Hamilton's books (Lyd painted her); Wee engaged to Henry Bartol
[Jan 1933] - To: Posie - From: Lydia (3021 N St., Washington, DC) - Subjects: Hoover portrait; Lydia going to White House; the Philippine question
Jan 20, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby gave a circus at Beech Hill; Arthur and Ev's 20th anniversary
Jan 23, [1933] - To: [Lydia] - From: Lou Hoover - Subject: birthday wishes to Lydia
Jan 29, 1933 - To: Lydia - From: Beatrice Proctor - Subjects: painting for exhibition; Lydia does Hoover portrait; comparison of Lydia and Charles Dana Gibson
Jan 30, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lydia in DC; Posie's opinion of Coward's play
Feb 7, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (in Washington, DC) - Subjects: Mrs. Hoover more tactful than Anne Choate; first ladies' portraits at White House; Ike Hoover (White House doorman); Sargent's Roosevelt; Zorus' Taft; Whistler paintings at Freer; the Coward play;Leland Stanford; Rob and old Hepburn; Gouve happy about marriage
Feb 14, 1933 - To: Posie - From: Margaret Chanler Aldrich - Subjects: thanks for welcoming Maddie, who married Bay's son, Christy Rand
Feb 20, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Hoover portrait; Lybba; Bobby's inaugural ode not to be in the New Yorker
Feb 22, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia drew "an old fellow"; Mrs. Brady of Girl Scouts liked Mrs. Hoover's portrait--anxious to hang it before inauguration; Queen's Husband with Barry Jones; Gertrude Watson and Kob; Lydia never sees Lybba; Roberto Emmet born in California of a Spanish mother--is Ned the father?
[1933] - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subject: Ros does a drawing of Henry
Mar 6, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: wedding of Wee and Henry Bartol--Gouve was best man, Ros maid of honor; Grenville (FDR's law partner) and Pauline at inauguration
Mar 12, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (in Washington, DC) - Subjects: Flo's arrival; Ellen Terry and Shaw
[Mar 1933] - To: ? - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia paints 4 Rutherfords; save the Met; FDR inauguration
Mar 23, [1933] - To: [Jane] - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bob Sherwood congratulated Noel Coward on play Cavalcade in which the Lunts hate their roles
Mar 29, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Wilfrid's portrait of Pope girl; Mrs. Roosevelt to approve portrait of Mrs. Hoover
Mar 30, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lybba looking after Posie; Eddie Morgan wants divorce; Lybba wants to go to England with Ros and Posie; Bob and Mary in England; Ros won golf tournament
[Mar 1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Eddie Morgan is in love with Fanny Preston
Apr 6, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: saw movie Cavalcade at Radio City; Archie back from British embassy in DC with Sherman Hoyt (nephew of Lady Lindsay)
Apr 13, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Florence and Langers sailed yesterday with the Shaws; Lydia's opinions of Shaw and Toscanini; Acropolis; LaFarge apartment; Lydia wants Mrs. Hoover information
Apr 17, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: dinner at Sherrewogue--family all together except Jane--Bessie White too; Lybba and boys; Marga and Frank; shocked at Hitler; Lybba to go abroad with Bobby and Mary in May; Grenville to be ambassador to Italy
Apr 26, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby and Posie to Lydia's studio to see ancestor portraits; Bobby sails Friday; Archie to Harvard; Wee detests Bartow; Lybba and Eddie; Susie
Apr 30, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: all family but Jane together at Sherrewogue; Bessie White; Lydia painted 3 boys in different styles; Posie gives up trip to England; Lybba to be in England; Archie to British embassy in DC; spoke to Anne Choate on Hoover portrait- payment delayed--Mrs. Hoover ignorant about art; Road to Rome sold to another movie company; Bobby wants Greta, but Joan Crawford gets it; "Jane Cow(l)"; Lydia rented the LaFarge apartment and her spare room to the Sherman Baldwins
May 5, [1933?] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: little Nelly very ill; Hardige Scholle and son Oliver; Bay; Gordon in nursing home; Wilfrid in Academy show; Eddie drunk--won't let Lybba go to Europe
May 10, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Posie (142 E 71st) - Subjects: Arthur Jr.'s spasms; Posie has to keep Mrs. Russell and can't go to England; Bobby and family, Lybba and boys
May 24, 1933 - To: Lydia - From: H. B. Platt - Subject: likes portrait of Tony
May 24, 1933 - To: Lydia - From: Charlotte P. Lyman (535 Park Ave.) - Subject: thanks for portrait
[1933] - To: Lydia - From: Lybba - Subject: goodbye before sailing
Jun 27, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (at High Valley) - Subjects: Lybba's break with Eddie; Alty Morgan's death; Nelly's illness;Constance H. is Edith Morgan's sister; Lydia's painting of little Mary in bridesmaid outfit; Dooly's good fortune; Susie found a Paris apartment
Jul 1, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lybba needs suitable provision from Alty Morgan estate; Cynthia's part in Devil's Disciple; Cynthia and Dooly to visit Jane; Archie and Sherman Hoyt to Cooperstown; Ros doing 6 drawings near Cleveland
Jul 7, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: FDR; Reunion in Vienna is now a movie; the Lunts and John Barrymore in a movie; Peter Pan movie; Geoffrey; Gouve and girl; Diana Wynyard in Cavalcade; Great Enton
Jul 23, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Nite to Talcotts' to bid Paige goodbye; Bay; Rose; Blanchard; Langers; Great Enton; Nelly's portrait by Lydia; Bobby to visit Jane, polishing Acropolis; no word from Lybba since she sailed; Athol Hays' death
Aug 14, [1933] - To: Lybba (in Europe) - From: Lydia (in Dedham, Mass.) -Subjects: Frank and Marga; Arthur Jr.'s ulcer; Hollister portrait; death of Eddie's father (Alty Morgan)
[Sep 1933] - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Barbara Rand; Ros paints 3 children; Bobby sailed to U.S. with Alice and Tucker Burr; Marc Connelly working on Acropolis
[1933] - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Lydia's portrait of mother and children and the Buffalo portrait; Acropolis complications--cast problems
Sep 29, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (in E. Aurora) - Subjects: Marion Hollister's visit; her portrait in Alice costume; Lydia painted Reggie Taylor in 1905; painted Taylor boys at Mt. Kisco
[Sep/Oct 1933] - To: [Jane] - From: Lydia (in Williamsville, New York) - Subjects: Lydia ill; Mildred Titus; Marian Hollister; Dooly to study in London; Gladys Cooper for Aspasia in Acropolis
Oct 8, [1933?] - To: Lybba - From: Winty - Subjects: jazz records; Jane Emmet turning Catholic?; Lybba felt bad in London
Oct 9, [1933] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Lydia's painting of Hollister child; Jane's 60th birthday; Lucy and Hugh Bredin; Little Mary's room at Great Enton; Lybba hopes for Eddie
Oct 24,1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lydia at the Taylors'; Lydia's illness; Acropolis; Richard was nude on the beach and greeted Susie Huntington; Posie reads Anthony Adverse
Nov 4, 1933 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (at Overshot) - Subjects: Lydia has been in hospital?; Dooly with Jane; heard Horowitz last night; Bob pleased with cast of Acropolis; Gilbert Miller and Marc Connelly took red-headed Clare for Acropolis (she modeled for the Emmets)
Nov 9, [1933?] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Mildred Titus' death in a car accident; Jack Chapman died; Frederick Schaefer dying
Nov 10, [1933] - To: Posie - From: Margaret Chanler Aldrich - Subject: A.C. Temple Emmet of past generation
Nov 21, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Marian Hollister; Susie's Paris concert in Dec.; Mrs. Taylor's niece ordered boys' portrait; Campbells' picture a success (the boys who put Lydia in hospital); now a portrait of a man who died of pneumonia; Kate Gibson with DeWolfe whose wife having breakdown like Madie; Art Workers' Fair
Nov 24, [1933] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Lybba's x-rays; Acropolis opens--Roger liked it; Leslie Howard; Dooly; Flo and Langers; Gladys in the play?
Nov 27, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bartow will divorce Nita; Penny at Bryn Mawr--affair with Roger Whitman; Campbell portrait; Tom Ewing portrait
Nov 28, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: ancestor portraits; Nite and Bartow to divorce--Bartow drinks; failure of Acropolis
Dec 2, 1933 - To: Posie - From: [Jane] - Subject: Acropolis with Gladys Cooper-- Ruth Draper saw it before her African trip
Dec 5, 1933 - To: Lydia - From: Marjorie Campbell - Subject: Hazard and Francis' portrait
Dec 5, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: no one in family can buy Emmet family portraits--Grenville will look at them in England; Dooly's classes in Britain; Graham Robertson
Dec 5, [1933] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Roger's opera; Acropolis; Lybba's letter; Elma Marsh worries about Susie's audience; Dooly sails on the 15th
Dec 11, [1933] - To: Lydia - From: Lybba - Subjects: Lydia ill; Eddie coming and both will go to Paris; Dean Jay boy (Dean Jay is head of Morgan bank, Paris); Susie's concert
Dec 12, 1933 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: Christmas card; Roger loved Acropolis; look forward to Reunion in Vienna
Dec 14, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby wants Jane's opinion of play; Betsy in play with Katharine Hepburn and Zebbie Whitehead; Grenville to be minister to Holland; Helen may buy ancestor portraits
Dec 14, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bancel LaFarge loves his job; Marga is expecting; Acropolis; Eddie bought Chesapeake place; Bay; Penny engaged to Roger Whitman; Lydia's portrait of Tom Ewing; Betsy and Zeb have parts in Hepburn's play The Lake
Dec 22, 1933 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Dooly's sculpture; MariaWhitehead and Zebby; Helen and Dicky made offer for ancestor portraits; Bobby writing a new play; Posie went to a party at Sidney Howard's and Polly Damrosch's; the Lunts in Reunion in Vienna; Geoffrey directed Betsy's play with Hepburn in DC; Ros doing portraits; Coward loved Zebbie in The Lake
Dec 26, 1933 - To: Lydia - From: Dewitt and Ralph Hanes - Subject: love portraits
Dec 27, [1933] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie and Pablo; Marga hemorrhaged during her pregnancy; war impending; Little Women movie with Hepburn; Mme. J. Francois Millet (nee Geraldine Reed of NY) is 84 years old and was married to Millet's son; Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo; Berkeley Square with Leslie Howard; Lydia sails June 27
Jan 5, 1934 - To: Lydia - From: Elizabeth - Subjects: Marcia's sad news; Lybba
Jan 6, 1934 - To: Lydia - From: Lucia - Subject: Tom's portrait
Jan 16, 1934 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Gabrielle Goddard, Mysie,and Madie; met Flo and Langers; Marga's miscarriage; worked on Marion Hollister portrait; Bob and Mary's marriage at an end--custody fight; Bobby took little Mary and escaped; Lybba in Italy; June Walker quote about Mary Sherwood
Jan 25, [1934] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby to Hollywood for Marie Antoinette and to Reno for divorce; Bob gets one third royalties to Reunion in Vienna
Jan 26, 1934 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: points of view on Susie's business; Lilli and Herm are socialists--shocks Susie; Mrs. Metcalfe's will in Bartow's firm; Lydia painted Woodward; Langers to Jamaica; Bobby to Hollywood yesterday to work on Marie Antoinette--Norma Shearer; Lybba arriving on the Acquitania
Feb 1, 1934 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Ros met Lybba's steamer--Lybba ill; party at Damrosch's for Walter's birthday; Marga may still have a baby; Bob and Mary's separation; Bob in Hollywood
Feb 7, 1934 - To: Lydia - From: Anne C. H___ - Subject: Tom Ewing's portrait
Feb 7, [1934] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: what has happened to Lybba?; Gerard Monod's cranky
[Feb 1934] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: death of Lybba (Elizabeth Emmet Morgan); funeral tomorrow; Eddie Morgan wanted Ros to visit him
Feb 11, 1934 - To: Lydia - From: Lucy and Hugo Beldin (in London) - Subjects: sympathy; Lydia to visit England next summer
Feb 11, 1934 - To: Lydia - From: Lucia - Subject: payment for portrait
Feb 12, 1934 - To: Lydia - From: Ella - Subjects: sympathy; Cecil Baring died